when hitler attacked the soviet union you
когда Гитлер напал на Советский Союз Ты
clearly say hitler is to blame that is not
чётко говоришь виноват Гитлер то есть не
to blame geographical location of the
виновато расположение географическое
ussr really hitler is to blame yes now
СССР правда виноват Гитлер Да теперь
Russia has attacked Ukraine who is to blame this is an
Россия напала на Украину Кто виноват это
extremely difficult question in itself in
крайне сложный вопрос на само на самом
fact a difficult question very mop question
деле сложный вопрос очень шваброй вопрос
really for
правда для
russians hello hello
россиян Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
where are you from Russia well that's clear city
откуда из России Ну это понятно город
tambo and you are
Тамбо А вы
khmelnitsky how are you doing normal how
Хмельницкий Как у вас дела Нормально Как
calm are you in tan bov were there any
у вас спокойно в тан бове были какие-то
arrivals
прилёты
no well how at all there were no arrivals in tambov it ca
Нет ну как вообще не было в Тамбове
n't be Well either I don't know
прилётов Не может быть Ну либо я не знаю
I'm
я
pretty la in the city everyone knows without
довольно ла в город все знают без
politics know well again here the question is how to
политики знают Ну опять тут вопрос как
present it because we don't have a whole series there what do you
подать ведь у нас же там не серия целая
think why Russia
какая-то как считаете почему Россия
attacked
напала на
Ukraine honestly I don't even know well I don't have
Украину честно даже не знаю Ну у меня
all the information
нет всей всей информации
full of plans and why
полный о планах А зачем
and I don't
а телевизору я не
believe in television so I became interested in
верю поэтому мне стало интересно
talking to people from this
пообщаться с людьми из этой
country understood how you support the
страны понял вы как поддерживаете
attack on Ukraine I don't support
нападение на Украину я не поддерживаю
war in any form because
войну в любом виде потому
then who do you think is to blame for the fact that
что как считаете тогда кто виноват в том
e war is
что э Война
going on I think that politics wine can
идёт Я считаю что полики вино
you give an example of these  politicians to
а можете пример этих политиков
call Well the
назвать Ну
leaders of the European Union Ukraine
руководители Европейского Союза Украины
Russia United States of America so And
России Соединённых Штатов Америки так А
how are Ukraine the EU and the United States
чем Украина ЕС и Соединённые Штаты
to blame that Russia attacked
виноваты что Россия напала на
Ukraine Well because what we so to
Украину Ну потому что то что нам так
speak the information that I have and
скажем та информация которой я владею а
Yagu said True information says
Ягу сказа Правдивая информация говорит
that there was an expansion of
что было расширение
NATO, respectively, the interests of
НАТО соответственно интересы
certain politicians were
определённых политиков были
affected explain again What does
затронуты ещё раз объясни Причём тут и
NATO have to do with it, for example, Latvia Lithuania
НАТО расширялась например Латвия Литва
Estonia joined NATO a long time ago Hungary joined
Эстония вошла давно в НАТО Венгрия вошла
Poland and they attacked Ukraine I can't
Польша а напали на Украину ничего не
understand anything Well because we well from the
могу понять ну потому что нам ну из той
information that I have Well, or rather,
информации которой я владею Ну вернее
which is in the public domain
которая в открытом доступе
no Look what information is there
находится нет Смотри какая информация
I know all sorts of you say your opinion
находится Я знаю всякая вы своё мнение
here look my opinion here is my
говорите вот смотрите моё мнение вот моё
opinion I will remove it now Here is everything Well so let's
мнение я сейчас уберу Вот все Ну так
say this path is slippery my
скажем скользкий вот этот путь моё
opinion is that a group of politicians did not
мнение что группа политиков не
agree a group of politicians - this is
договорилась группа политиков - это
specifically not specific there Russia and yes
конкретно не конкретны там Россия и да
look again Well for example look
ещё раз смотрите Ну например смотрите
If you and I Yes we try to agree I
Если мы с вами Да пробуем договориться Я
want to buy potatoes from you for example at the market
хочу у вас например на базаре купить
and you want to sell potatoes we did
картошку а вы хотите продать картошку мы
not agree on the price  and I went and filled
не договорились по цене и я пошёл набил
your kiosk we are to blame because we did not
вам и киоск виноваты мы потому что не
agree or I am to blame for filling your
договорились или виноват я что набил вам
kiosk not specifically in this example
киоск не в конкретно в этом примере
that you are talking about of course you would be like this
который вы говорите конечно вы были бы
and here absolutely look the
вот так и тут тут абсолютно смотрите
politicians did not agree Well they did not
политики не договорились Ну не
agree They are not obliged to
договорились Они же не обязаны
agree yes that is the
договориться да
Agreement is a voluntary thing yes
тобто Договор - это Добровольная вещь да
people agree so that they have
люди договариваются чтобы у ним было
some there interesting yes and they attacked
какие-то там интересно да а напали Вы
Why did you Well I did not attack Well Russia is your
зачем Ну нападал не я Ну Россия ваша
country that is well we did not agree Well
страна то есть ну не договорились Ну
Negotiate further try Look
Договаривайтесь дальше пробуйте Смотрите
here you are just saying I do not have
вот вы как раз и говорите я не владею
all the information that is why
всей информации которая есть зачем
why and for what purpose
почему и для чего
on the dave yes How do you as a citizen think
на даве да Как вы Как гражданин думаете
who is to blame And why am I telling you the
кто виноват И почему я вам и говорю
politicians are to blame Well what am I saying here is
виноваты политики Ну в чём я говорю вот
what Emmanuel Macron is to blame for that
в чём Эммануэль макрон виноват что
Russia attacked
Россия напала на
Ukraine Well again I do not have all the
Украину Ну опять же у меня нет всей всей
information stop if I do not have all the information you just
информации стоп если нету всей ты сейчас
said with your lips the politicians are to blame
своими губами сказал виноваты политики
That is you put the blame on them
То есть ты на них ты на них вину положил
now I say so answer for your bazaar Why are
тепер говорю так ответь за базар Почему
you not to blame I do not know
не виноваты ты говоришь я не знаю вот
no And I  I'll give you an example like this and for
нет А я приведу пример как вот и
example like how you gave me for example there are
например как как вы мне привели например
two people here is one the Second and I
есть два человека вот один Второй и мне
receive information that for example This
приходит информация что например Этот
person wants to attack me Well
человек хочет на меня напасть Ну
take my money For example
отобрать у меня деньги Например
and that is I I see this person I
и то есть я я вижу этого человека
trust information that is my friend
информации Я доверяю то есть мой друг
says that he saw he heard a
говорит что вот он видел он слышал
conversation how this person is walking he got
разговор как этот человек идёт он
ready he has a knife with him for example
подготовился у него с собой там например
there Well I'm speaking figuratively and he is walking
нож там Ну я образно говорю и он идёт
towards me that is my actions wait
вот ко мне то есть мои действия ждать
until this person starts on me Let's Yes
пока этот человек начнёт на меня Давайте
you gave a good example Let's
Да хороший вы пример сказали Давайте
if you yes uh
если вы да
attacked and the person Yes the police arrive Yes
ээ напали и человека Да приезжает
who will be to blame for this beating you
Да кто будет виноват в этом избиении вы
Or that person too because you will
Или тот человек тоже потому что вы
say well I had information that he
скажете ну у меня была информация что он
wanted to take money from me look
хотел у меня забрать деньги у смотрите
no but let's then I will say No well then
нет а а давайте тогда я скажу Не ну так
stop stop you said yes yes you you
стоп стоп ты ж ты же говорил да да ты ты
look you really Yes person Yes because you
смотри ты реально Да человека Да потому
say look I had
что говоришь смотрите у меня была
information that he wanted me
информация что он хотел меня
Yes who will be to blame Well of course I pose you will
Да кто будет виноват Ну конечно я поза
put you in jail but I will be right because I am alive
посадят но я буду прав потому что я жив
No no no again
Нет нет нет ещё раз
here is the right wine Wine Because you  look
вот пра вино Вино Потому что ты смотри
you decided for some of your own reasons
ты из каких-то своих соображений решил
decided him Because you thought that it was
решил его Потому что ты подумал что это
he who wanted you Look Well we will be on not
он тебя хочет Смотри Ну мы будем наты не
for our own reasons I see that he is
из своих соображений я вижу что он на
coming at me with a weapon Well stop stop stop
меня идёт с оружием Ну вот стоп стоп
no coming with a weapon this is For example
стоп нет идёт с оружием это Например
if Ukraine attacked
если Украина нападала на
Russia look to attack is already an action to
россит смотри напасть - это уже действие
commit I see here is a person here conditionally
совершить я вижу вот человек вот условно
I have there conditionally there are 15 let's do this let's do
У меня есть там ну условно там 15 давай
this then your neighbor your
так давай так значит твой сосед твой
neighbor lives for example in his
сосед живёт например в своей
apartment you rush to his house and him
квартире ты вырываешь к нему в дом и его
Because it seemed to you that he would
Потому что тебе показалось что он будет
attack you so I understand Well not
на тебя нападать так я понимаю Ну не
exactly he is coming at me already with a weapon For
совсем он идёт на меня уже с оружием Вот
example he is coming at me with a weapon and
например он он идёт на меня с оружием и
I have every reason for example to
у меня есть все основания например
believe that so come on stop stop where
полагать что так давай стоп стоп где
Come on Where is Emmanuel Macron or Ukraine
Давай Где Эммануэль макрон или Украина
was coming with weapons to Russia Well
шла с оружием на Россию А ну
say no I'm not saying no No well you you do
скажи нет Я же не говорю не Не ну ты ты
n't come on come on tell me where Ukraine
ты ж не давай давай скажи где Украина
was coming with weapons to Russia I You look You
шла с оружием на России я Ты смотри Ты
see You you are jumping at I
видишь Ты ты перескакивает у Я же
Initially I said I don't have this
Изначально сказал у меня нет этой
information I  I know that there are politicians they
информации Я знаю что есть политики они
negotiate they have some specific
договариваются у них конкретные какие-то
interests of their own and they negotiate on this
интерес и они договариваются по этому
issue again again look come on let's do it
вопросу ещё раз ещё раз смотри давай так
now Ukraine was going to Russia with weapons
давай мы сечас Украина шла с оружием на
I don't know why you why you
Россию я не знаю зачем ты зачем ты
are giving this example look really
приводишь этот пример смотри реально
look I am giving an example that there was
смотри я привожу пример такой что была
information in the public domain that
информация в открытом доступе что
Ukraine Well Donbass and specifically the region
Украина Ну Донбасс и конкретно область
Well
Ну
there Donbass They wanted to separate
там Донбасс Они хотели отдели
p you are already jumping The war has been going on since
п ты уже перескакивает Война идёт с
2014 I am asking why
четырнадцатого года я спрашиваю почему
you attacked Ukraine in
вы напали на Украину в четырнадцатом
2014 having captured Crimea Donetsk and Lugansk Here
году захватив Крым Донецк и Луганск Вот
we have the information that I
вот у нас вот та информация которой я
have that is which Well in the public
владею то есть которую Ну в открытом
domain It says that these
доступе Она говорит о том что эти
regions decided to separate no so look
области решили отделиться нет так смотри
how they decided there Russian troops entered and
как решили там российские войска зашли и
then like held a referendum
дальше уже типа проводили референдум
Look I don't have this information Look like that
Смотри я не владею этой информа Вот вот
stop look I look again watch
так смотри стоп смотри я ещё раз смотри
If you don't have it Come on let's
смо Если ты не владеешь Давай давай
build our conversation on the information that
построим наш разговор на информации
you  you own if look if you
которой ты владеешь если смотри если ты
look if you don't own Vlada No, don't interrupt
смотри если ты не Владе Нет не перебивай
No, we'll build our conversation the way I
Нет мы построим свой разговор так как я
communicate with people if I don't own the
общаюсь с людьми если я не владею
information I'm not talking Yes, for example, I don't
информацией Я не говорю Да например я не
own the information I'm not talking about you Who are
владею информацией Про тебя я не говорю
you yes And
Кто ты есть да И
what Therefore, look, therefore, let's rely on the
что Поэтому смотри поэтому давай мы
information that you
будем опираться на информацию которой ты
own because well, it's stupid to talk and
владеешь потому что ну глупо говорить а
then ask, answer, you say, I don't
потом спрашиваю ответь ты говоришь я не
own this information So Hugo go, in
владею этой информацией Так что Уго го в
that case, we need to build a conversation
таком случае на разговор нужно строить
that I assume about That's how you talk I
что я предполагаю о Вот так ты говори Я
assume I assume because it's
предполагаю я предполагаю потому что
true Let's then assume go
правда Давай тогда предполага го
pre I can't check the info that you
пре Я не могу проверить ту инфо что ты
assume I
предполагаешь
assume that someone's interests of
Я предполагаю что чьи-то интересы
some politicians were
каких-то политиков были
affected so interestingly nutria the
затронуты так интересно нутрия
activities of any people of the country
деятельность любых людей стран
affect someone's interests Yes, for example,
затрагивают чьи-то интерес Да например
any I I assume question And why did they
любой я я предполага вопрос А зачем
attack Well, I assume that there was, let's
напали ну я предполагаю что там было так
say, something related to
скажем задействовано что-то связанное с
oil and gas involved Because I don't believe
нефтью и газом Потому что я не верю
in romantic slogans at all there
совершенно в романтические лозунги там
Freedom, I still understood something, that is,
Свобода ещё чтото всё понял то есть
something happened with oil and gas, that is,
что-то было с нефтью и газом то есть
Ukraine and Europe and America are not to blame,
Украина и Европа и Америка не виноваты
it was Russia that needed something, oil.
это России нужно было что-то нефть
Not really. You see again, I can assume
Не совсем я опять ты видишь я могу
that let's assume, can you
предполагать что давай предположи можешь
assume, What was
предположить В чём была вина
Ukraine's fault? Well, Ukraine's fault is in its
Украины Ну вина Украины в её
geographical
географическом
location. So stop. That is, for example,
расположении Так стоп То есть например
your fault may be that you
твоя вина может быть в том что у тебя
have an apartment in this place. Yes, of course, but have
есть квартира в этом месте Да конечно а
n't there been such situations
Разве Разве таких ситуаций не было где
somewhere, wait, do I understand correctly that,
то есть подожди я правильно понимаю что
for example, a
например
neighbor comes to you, yes, or
тебя приходит сосед да или
there, and in court they tell you that you are still
там а на суде тебе говорят ты ещё
guilty because your apartment is located
виноватый потому что у тебя квартира как
on the fifth floor, well, there are many such examples.
раз на пятом этаже ну а таких примеров
Stop. In Russia, they can convict a
много Стоп У вас в России могут осудить
person and find him guilty only of the
человека признать его виновным только в
fact that his apartment is located. Yes,
том что у него квартира расположена да
look again, you are now saying such an Obvious
смотри ты сейчас говоришь такой Явный
text, what
текст
can you [ __ ] again, no, look at
то что можно сри ещё раз нет смотри
the concept of guilt, the concept of guilt,
понятие вины понятие вины
it seems to imply some
оно как бы предполагает какие-то
actions of a person. Yes, actions or
действия человека Да действия или
inactions. Yes, for example, you
бездействия Да например вот вы что-то
did something bad, you are guilty, or you did not
сделали плохое вы виноваты или вы не
do, you did not save someone, you are guilty. Yes,
сделали не спасли кого-то вы виноваты да
what  just simply geographic
В чём просто просто географическое
location cannot be Look I
положение не может быть Смотри Я я
assumed but to answer
предположил но чтобы вот ответить на
this question You need to visit
этот вопрос Нужно побывать тя на
some
каком-то
closed at least see some
закрытом хотя бы видеть какие-то
documents well we assume we already Understand
документы ну мы предполагаем мы уже Поня
that you don't have them documents you
что у тебя нет них докумен ты
assume but look if you say
предполагаешь но смотри если ты говоришь
that Ukraine is to blame I ask can you
что виновата Украина Я спрашиваю можешь
assume the World Cup you say
предположить ЧМ ты говоришь
geographic location cannot be
географическим расположение не может
geographic location be to
географического расположение быть вино
blame Look let's say for example So now
Смотри вот давай например Так сейчас
more or less something is becoming Clear
более-менее становится что-то Понятно
World War II somehow Clear
Вторая мировая война как-то Понятно
Because some documents there are
Потому что какие-то документы там
declassified and e something is
рассекречены и е чтото
considered that the Soviet Union wanted to attack
считат что Советский Союз хотел напасть
Germany no look what it wanted is
на Германию те нет смотри то что хотел
generally unimportant ho attacked Hitler
это вообще до лампочки хо напал Гитлер
Who attacked the Soviet Wait Who attacked the Soviet Union
Кто напал на Советский Подожди Кто напал
not the Soviet Union
на Советский Союз не Советский Союз
attacked Nazi Germany Yes that's it No
напал нацистской Германия Да
questions come on so who is to blame for the fact that
всё Вопросов нет давай так кто виноват в
Germany attacked the Soviet
том что Германия напала на Советский
Union here and here it
Союз вот а вот здесь как раз и
begins Look I'll warn you You
начинается Смотри я тебя предупрежу Ты
know that in the Russian Federation yes let's
знаешь что в Российской Федерации да
say criminally  punishable denial of guilt of
скажем уголовно наказуемо отрицание вины
Nazi Germany and recognition and
гитлеровской Германии и признание и
recognition of guilt of the Soviet Union I will simply
признание вины Советского Союза Я просто
warn you I will not in any case Personally
тебя предупрежу я ни в коем случае Лично
I do not deny I am talking about the fact that there is an
я не отрицаю Я говорю о том что есть
opinion of other people no yours I am
мнение других людей нет твоё мне
interested in your opinion I am not interested I
интересно твоё мнение мне не интерес я
will communicate with other people I will ask
буду общаться с другими людьми я спрошу
their opinion your opinion who is to blame for the fact that
их мнение твоё мнение кто виноват в том
Hitler attacked the Soviet
что Гитлер напал на Советский
Union well Hitler is official look official
Союз ну Гитлер офици смотри официальная
point of view your opinion yours is not official
точку зре твоё мнение твоё не официально
And yours Unfortunately I my
А твоё К сожалению я моё
opinion it does not contradict the
мнение оно не противоречит
official official position And what
официальному официальной позиции А что к
unfortunately but I
сожалении а я
misspoke that is look when Hitler
оговорился то есть смотри когда Гитлер
attacked the Soviet Union You clearly
напал на Советский Союз Ты чётко
say Hitler is to blame that is not
говоришь виноват Гитлер то есть не
to blame geographical location
виновато расположение географическое
USSR really Hitler is to blame
СССР правда виноват Гитлер
Now when Russia look because
Теперь когда росия смотри потому что у
now we have an extensive source of
нас сейчас есть обширный источник
information documents in my opinion very not
информации документы по-моему очень не
again look very simply Hitler attacked the
ещё раз смотри очень просто Гитлер напал
USSR everything is clearly to blame the one who attacked
на СССР всё чётко виноват тот кто напал
Hitler not
Гитлер не
location population Everything now Russia
расположение население Всё теперь Россия
attacked Ukraine Who is to blame Well in the fact
напала на Украину Кто виноват Ну в том
that it is
что она
conducting if we say the laws of the
проводит если мы говорим законы
Russian Federation special  military
Российской Федерации специальную военную
operation Well of course it is Russia that is initiating it it is
операцию Ну конечно инициатор России она
conducting Who is to blame Well how is it to
проводит Кто виноват ну как как
blame logic I answered you a
виноват логика я тебе ответил
special military operation is being conducted by
специальную военную операцию проводит
Russia So who is to
Россия Так кто виноват в том что Россия
blame that Russia is conducting a special military operation on the territory of Ukraine Well how is it to blame it is
территории Украины Ну ну как виноват она
conducting a special military operation
проводит специальную военную опера
people are dying Who is to blame that these
умирают люди Вот кто виноват что эти
people are
люди
dying Well how are politicians dying
умирают ну как как умирают политики
and Zelensky is to blame or the one who
которые и Зеленский виноват или тот кто
started his Who is to
начал сво Кто
blame Well this is an extremely difficult
виноват Ну это это это крайне сложный
question in fact a
вопрос на самом деле сложный вопрос
very difficult question a mop question really for Russia you
очень шваброй вопрос правда для России
understand the point they didn't
понимаешь ведь смысл они не
agree right they didn't agree
договорились правильно они не
Well look super
договорились Да вот смотри супер
right they didn't agree And there is no
правильно они не договорились А
one to blame Let's go from the opposite right
винова нет Давай пойдём от обратного вот
now for example What do I see Although I am a
сейчас например Я что вижу Хотя я
person far from politics but I watch for
человек далёкий от политики но я смотрю
example some YouTube what I see what
например какой-нибудь YouTube что я вижу
Trump is calling for there another unwinding once again Trump war is going on yes
Трамп ещ размот ещ раз трам война идт да
Russia Look here the state of
Россия Смотри вот жила государство
Ukraine lived with its politicians the state of
Украина со своими политиками государство
Russia they agreed on something there but didn't
России они что-то там договаривались но
agree Well okay didn't
не договорились Ну окей не
agree And why did Russia attack
договорились А зачем напал россие на
Ukraine Well look there is there  the official
Украину Ну смотри есть есть официальная
position that there is oppression in Ukraine
позиция что в Украине идёт притеснение
super yes in Ukraine yes Ukraine oppresses
супер да в Украине да Украина притесняет
Russians Ukraine oppresses Belarusians
русских Украина притесняет белорусских
Ukraine oppresses Well I don't have
Украина притесняет
this information
Ну это вот этой информации у меня нету
so I don't have it that is imagine you
так я я не владею то есть представь ты
ask me again look we
меня спрашиваешь ещё раз смотри мы с
agreed another 10 minutes or 15
тобой договорились ещё 10 минут или 15
if you don't have it You don't voice it well I do
если не владеешь Не озвучиваешь ну я я
n't have it that is then I don't have an
не владею то есть тогда у меня нет на
answer to this to your question just yes
этот на твой вопрос ответа просто да
if there is no question answer why then do you
если нет вопрос ответа зачем ты тогда
put the blame not on the one who attacked
вину накладываешь не на того кто напал
Ukraine And also on other people Look
на Украину А ещё на других людей Смотри
if if then to sum up the conversation
если если тогда подытожить разговор
when you asked me this question
когда ты мне задал вот этот вопрос У
I would simply have all my remarks
меня бы просто все мои реплики были у
I have no answer to this Well if we
меня на это нет ответа Ну если вот
assume So I simply have
предположить Так у меня просто на это
no answer to this why is Russia conducting
нет ответа вот зачем Россия проводит
its A what ho A what does your government
сво А что хо А что ваше государство
say What are the goals of the special military
говорит Какие цели специальной военной
operation
операции
I I'm telling you I'm far from politics ok
я Я же говорю я далёк от политики хорошо
ok why why did your government
а хорошо зачем зачем ваше государство
then take and include Crimea Donetsk
тогда взяла и включила Крым Донецк
Lugansk this Zaporozhye region and
Луганск эту запорожскую область и
Kherson to the Russian
херсонскую в состав Российской
Federation I have no answer I am saying
Федерации у меня нет ответа Я же говорю
any everything the whole dialogue will be built on
любой всё весь диалог будет строиться на
this here is a
вот таком
question your question and my answer
вот вопрос твой вопрос и мой ответ у
Well and my answer I have no answer
меня Ну и мой ответ у меня нет ответа
here Actually how how will all this all be
вот Собственно как как это всё всё будет
built And you should come here to talk about
строиться А ты дол сюда поговорить о
politics No no way I came out to
политики Да нет ни в коем случае я вышел
talk I became interested in how
поговорить мне стало интересно как
Ukrainians feel because I
чувствуют себя украинцы потому что я
saw for example that is I
увидел например то есть я правильно
understand correctly Yes what look Your country is
понимаю Да что смотри Твоя страна
killing people in my country in Ukraine and
убивает людей в моей стране в Украине и
instead of figuring out why it is
ты вместо того чтобы разобраться почему
doing this can you somehow stop it
она это делает может как-то остановить
you came out look the very first moment I
ты вышел смотри самый первый момент я
now also I understand you are a blogger
вот сейчас тоже я понимаю ты блогер вот
I have already spoken with some blogger about this question
я с каким-то уже блогером на этот вопрос
and he asked me this question Here
говорил и он мне задал такой вопрос Вот
you stop tell me how how to
ты остановить скажи мне как как
stop this is generally possible for one
остановить это вообще возможно одному
person no so nothing depends on you
человеку нет так от тебя ничего не
in Russia this is clear Here
зависит в России это же понятно Вот вот
I agree you are slaves of the system you
я согласен вы там рабы системы вы ничего
can't do anything you Even if you
не можете сделать вы Ты даже если
come out with an empty white sheet of paper you
выйдешь с пустым белым листочком тебя
The question is different what why
Вопрос в другом что почему ты вместо
instead of figuring out sit down Why is your
того чтобы разобраться сесть Почему твоя
country killing people in my country
страна убивает людей в моей стране
look look there is such an expression
смотри смотри есть такой выражение
true  - this is something that can be verified I
правда - это то что можно проверить я
can verify that Yes, there is a special
могу проверить что Да идёт специальная
military operation, that's what we
военная операция она у нас так
call it, and Russian soldiers,
называется и российские военнослужащие
as well as Ukrainian soldiers, are
так же как и украинские военнослужащие
killing each other This is me Well, this is It's
друг друга убивают Это я Ну это Это
just a logical conclusion All other
просто логичный вывод все остальные
questions about Who is to blame, what Well, what is
вопросы о том Кто виноват что Ну что что
happening, there is a small nuance,
происходит есть есть маленький нюанс
look, Ukrainian soldiers
смотри украинские военнослужащие
are destroying the invaders, and Russian
уничтожают захватчиков а российские
soldiers are killing people
военнослужащие да делают убийство людей
in a foreign country Well, again, you see and
в чужой стране Ну опять ты видишь
say Listen, why is yours I
говоришь Слушай а зачем вот твоя Я не
can't understand Here you went out to talk to the
могу понять Вот ты вышел пообщаться с
Ukrainians What about Well, the first moment,
украинцами О чём Ну первый момент как
I just saw the story And
раз я увидел сюжет А
tsk, wait, look, now, look, that
тцк подожди смотри сечас ещ смотри то
is, your country Your country attacked
есть у тебя страна Твоя страна напала на
my country So, so, so you have a
мою страну так так так ты имеешь
huge amount of information in which you
огромный объём информации в котором
need to figure out why it attacked
нужно разобраться почему она напала
Maybe it's wrong But you watch
может она не права но ты смотришь
some stories about what's going on inside Ukraine and You
какие-то сюжеты что там внутри Украины и
want to talk about what's happening
Хочешь пообщаться о том что происходит
inside Ukraine Well, look, there is a concept of
внутри Украины Ну смотри есть понятие
truth - this is something that can be verified
правда - это то что можно проверить ещё
again, look again, look Let's do it this way I'm right, I
раз смотри ещё раз смотри Давай так я я
want to understand correctly, look  in
пра не я правильно хочу понять смотри в
Russia there are a lot of things that
России есть куча всяких вещей которые
can be checked but your country Russia
можно проверить но твоя страна Россия
kills people in my country Ukraine you
убивает людей в моей стране Украине ты
instead of these 3 years and already the
вместо того чтобы эти 3 года и уже
fourth year Yes go try to
четвёртый год Да идёт попытаться
figure out some things that
разобраться в каких-то вещах которые
can be checked in Russia you are interested in
можно проверить в России тебя интересуют
things that happen in Ukraine the truth is
вещи которые происходят в Украине правда
I have no way to check this
у меня нет возможности проверить эту
information Because in order for me to
информацию Потому что чтобы мне её
check it I need to talk to the
проверить мне надо поговорить с
original source in this case our
первоисточником в данном случае наш
president your president Yes I mean
президент ваш президент Да я имею виду
let's do it everything else is what's going on in
давай так всё остальное это то чтом го в
Russia yes well for example
России да хорошо например
you can talk to Russians yes about
ты можешь поговорить с россиянами да о
corruption and check of course yes I understand
коррупции и проверить конечно да понял
why you don't talk to them about corruption
почему ты не говоришь с ними о коррупции
but go out with Ukrainians talk about something
а выходишь с украинцами поговори что-то
there the story you saw look the
там сюжет ты видел смотри в том-то и
thing is that I live here and I see it myself
дело что я-то здесь живу и я это сам
I don't even need to look
вижу мне даже смотреть не надо Ты из
What city are you from Well Tambov Tambov And for
какого города Ну Тамбов Тамбов А
example talk to Muscovites Well what's
например с москвичами поговорить Ну что
there in Moscow
там в Москве
Well what's the difference No well there is a difference is it
Ну какая разница Не ну есть разница там
really like that Yes no about
действительно ли так Да нет о с
talk to Chechens like they have in
чеченцами пообщаться типа как у них в
Grozny for example is there freedom of speech in
Грозном например есть ли Свобода слова в
Grozny can they be there  rally
Грозном могут они ли там митинг провести
Well, freedom of speech I don't believe that
Ну свободу слова я вообще не верю что
it exists anywhere, yeah, for example,
она где-то есть ага ну например може
maybe Can it be in Chechnya Yes, a person like to
Может ли в Чечне Да человек типа что-то
say something against Kadyrov That's how he would go out
сказать против Кадырова Вот так бы вышел
and ask Chechens on chatroulette
бы и в чатрулетке поспрашивать
Well, what What's clear he
чеченцев Ну что Что понятно
can't say anything about him Why can he Well,
ничего не может сказать про него Почему
that's how I asked No, maybe he can,
может может Ну так спросил Не может
but for example, I haven't
может быть и сможет но я например не
come across this information about this region,
встречал эту информацию про этот регион
so on the contrary, I would just talk to them
так вот наоборот как раз бы с ними
to meet Well, that is, no
пообщался чтобы встретить Ну то есть нет
Look, I came across it again And what is the capital of the
Смотри опять мне попался А какая столица
Khakassi Republic of
хакаси республики
Khakassia, Khavr not, aka, it's in Dagestan Yes, you do
Хакасии хавр не ака это в Дагестане
n't know what you have there, in short, what
Да не знаешь что у тебя там короче какие
Republics, yes, but you're drawn to
Республики что да но тебя тянет
talk to the Ukrainians you're
пообщаться с украинцами которых вы
killing, what do they have there in Ukraine, no,
убиваешь что у них там в Украине да не
look I'm not drawn I watched the
так смотри Меня не тянет Я посмотрел
story Well, look, the question is in
сюжет Да так смотри вопрос в
Russia, look, in Russia there are a huge
России смотри в России огромное
number of stories, there are all sorts For
количество сюжетов есть всяких Вот
example,
например что
in the Sakha Republic Where gold and
в Республике Саха Где добывают золото
diamonds are mined Yes, a lot of people live in wooden
алмазы Да куча людей живёт в деревянных
barracks You didn't want to Poa with people from
бараках Вот ты не хотел Поа с людьми из
again  look You see how you pose the
опять смотри Ты видишь как ставишь
question but I came across this story yeah
вопрос но мне попался этот сюжет да
Okay, let's do it this way super I get it tell me
Хорошо давай так супер я понял расскажи
what stories about Russia you've come across in the
какие сюжеты про Россию тебе попадались
last month come on Yes practically
последний месяц давай Да практически
none as in none Well, well then none
никаких как никаких Ну ну так никаких
Because I'm not particularly interested in
Потому что я не особо интересуюсь
politics and And how do you come across a
политикой и А как тебе попадается про
story about Ukraine And you don't
Украину сюжет А про Россию не попадается
come across a story
нет про тцк мне попался сюжет из Да а
about Russia no about tsk I came across a
почему про Россию вот я не могу понять
story from Yes and why about Russia I can't understand you don't come across stories about Russia And you
про Россию тебе не попадаются сюжеты А
came across a story about Ukraine How does that happen No well
про Украину попался Как так получается
maybe I did
Нет ну про Россию может быть мне и
come across some stories about Russia Yes which ones Tell me Look you live in Russia
попадались Да какие Расскажи Смотри ты
You watch Russian
живёшь в России Ты смотришь российские
news read Russian telegrams
Новости читаешь российские телеграмы
Tell me for example in the last telegrams
Расскажи например за последний телеграмы
I didn't Read Okay it doesn't matter in short you you
я не Чита Ладно неважно короче ты ты
live in the Russian information space
живёшь в информационном пространстве
Yes tell me in the last
российском Да расскажи за последний
month can you name five stories that
месяц можешь назвать пять сюжетов какие
you remember from Russia none How is that oh well
тебе запомнились из России никаких Как
I didn't watch them
это так а ну я их и не я их и не смотрел
Okay, let's do it this way in the last year can you
Хорошо давай так за последний год можешь
remember some story on Russian
какой-то сюжет вспомнить по российской
topics Yes none I don't watch
тематике Да никаких я я не смотрю
stories on Russian topics Where did you
сюжетов по российской тематике А где ты
see them  about TTK plotne I wonder how
видел про ТТК сюжетне Интересно а как
some blogger from Ukraine something he And
какой-то блогер С Украины что-то он А
why No look Why did you watch a
зачем Нет смотри Зачем ты смотрел
blogger from Ukraine No he came across me that
блогера из Украины Нет он мне попался то
is I open YouTube and I
есть Я открываю YouTube и у меня
naturally have some everything is super yes
естественно есть какие-то всё супер да
look when you open YouTube except for the
смотри когда ты открываешь YouTube кроме
blogger from Ukraine What other
блогера Украины Какие ещё у тебя
recommendations do you have Well related to music
рекомендации есть Ну связанные с музыко
with music with computers with no no I can't
с музыкой с компьютерами с не не не могу
look if you came across a blogger then
смотри если тебе попался блогер значит и
other news some kind of
другие новостные какие-то типа
political hits Which of the
политические были попадания Кто из
Russians did you come across not from the Russians to me no
русских тебе попадался не из русских мне
one is a half Take it now on your phone
никто не пол Возьми сейчас на телефоне
Show your recommendations Open the page
Покажи свои рекомендации Открой страницу
tube Let's see now I have a
туба Давай сейчас посмотрим у меня
very cheap phone let's see Well
телефон очень такой дешёвый посмотрим Ну
just for fun I'm interested in what
просто ради интереса Мне интересно какие
recommendations you have which Ukrainian
у тебя рекомендации какой украинский
blogger will be and I'm on my phone
блогер будет и воз я сечас с телефона
now Show it now well I don't watch on my phone
Покажи сейчас ну у меня я в телефоне не
I have a Xiaomi redi 7 and what well how to
смотрю у меня Xiaomi redi 7 и что ну как
watch there well you'll open YouTube anyway For
там смотреть ну так YouTube всё равно
example look I can
откроешь Вот например смотри я могу
say now I have Maxim
сейчас сказать у меня есть вот Максим
Katz for example came out here Russian yes
Кац например вышел вот российский вот да
what have you been doing in the last year from Maxim  Katz do you
что ты за последний год из Максима каца
remember Well, about Trump, I've been
помнишь Ну вот про трампа я
talking for the last year
последний год мне попался вот этот сюжет
about Trump,
про трам
what about you Well, tell me what's in the
что емен те Ну расскажи что в
recommendations, so on and on and on we
рекомендациях вот так дальше дальше
go if we're talking about the
дальше идём если мы говорим о
political of this whole
политической всей этой
topic Maxim Katz Evgeny Panasenkov I have here,
темы Максим Кац Евгений панасенков у
so on and ...
россиянину так Да кстати вот интересный
Duma so
Государственную Думу
this will be a very difficult
так это это будет очень сложный
question No, I will not answer it well And
вопрос Нет я на него не отвечу хорошо А
who is your Chairman of the Government of the
кто у вас Председатель правительства
Russian
Российской
Federation I will not answer it either Your State Duma is
Федерации тоже не отвечу Госдума у вас
headed by Volodin and the government is
Володин возглавляет а правительство
Mishustin now an interesting question Why are
Мишустин теперь вопрос интересный Почему
you a resident of the Russian Federation and do not know
ты житель Российской Федерации не знаешь
who the head of your parliament is Who makes
кто у вас глава парламента Кто принимает
laws for
законы для
you Who is your head of government and none
ва Кто у вас глава правительства и никто
of you know yes but you are
из вас не знает да вот но тебя
interested in Trump I wonder why not Well and
интересует Трамп вот интересно почему
why can't he
нет Ну а почему он меня не может
interest me yes Well look look your
интересовать да Ну смотри смотри на твою
life is not affected by Trump somewhere overseas
жизнь влияет не Трамп где-то за океаном
he affects the lives of Americans your
он влияет на жизнь американцев на твою
life in Russia in Tambov in this God-
жизнь в России в Тамбове в этом Богом
forsaken Tambov Yes
забытом Тамбове Да
Putin affects you know him the
влияет Путин ты его знаешь влияет
State Duma affects which makes
Государственная Дума которая принимает
laws by which you live Tut the
законы по которым ты жив Вт
government which is responsible for the
правительство которое отвечает за
economy yes that is Mishustin and Volodin
экономику да то есть Мишустин и Володин
they are directly responsible for your
они прямо отвечают за твоё
well-being for the rules by which
благосостояние за те правила по которым
you live by which you are fined or
ты живёшь по которым тебя штрафуют или
not fined And so on that is and you are
не штрафуют И так дальше то есть и тебе
not interested in what is happening with you
не интересно то что происходит у тебя
why you have
почему у тебя вот Ключевая ставка стала
Nabiullina raised the key rate Yes the head of the National Bank of
набиулина подняла Да глава Нацбанка
your Central Bank that's up to  there that's why because of
вашего Центробанка вот до там вот почему
this the mortgage will be Dear,
изза этого ипотека будет Дорогая а
why are prices rising Why aren't you
почему цены растут Почему тебя не
interested in what your officials do,
интересует то что делают твои чиновники
top officials But are you interested in
топ чиновники А тебя интересует
Trump Well, I just became interested, that
Трамп Ну мне просто стало интересно то
is, I am a person outside of politics who Yes,
есть я человек вне политики кото Да вот
you are outside of politics but you are interested in the
ты вне политики но тебе интересен
politician Trump Imagine That is, you tell me
политик Трамп Представь То есть ты мне
then it turns out you want to
вот тогда получается ты мне хочешь
tell me that I what I need so that it would be
сказать что мне что мне надо чтобы мне
interesting to me No, I want to raise
было интересно не Нет я я хочу поднять
Look, I am a psychologist Yes, I am a psychologist I have
Смотри я психолог Да я психолог у меня
18 years of practice in 2 years it will be the
18 лет практики через 2 года будет
twentieth I am interested in why people
двадцатой Мне интересно почему люди
watch this or that Here you are a person in
смотрят то или не то Вот ты человек в
Russia who lives in Russia on whom
России который живёт в России от
your life depends in the literal sense from the activities of the State Duma of the Russian Federation government
зависит твоя жизнь в прямом этом смысле
And what surrounds you but you are not
Да и то что тебя окружает но ты не
interested in politics Yes, you don't even know them, you don't even
интересуешься политикой Да не знаешь их
know anything but you were suddenly
даже не знаешь ничего но тебя резко
interested in the politics of the state of
заинтересовала политика государства
Ukraine and the politics of the state of the
Украина и политика государства
United States of America Why is it that
Соединённые Штаты Америки Почему так
yours
твоя
Look, it was not politics that interested you but a
Смотри не политика заинтересовал а
politician, a politician, for example, yes, me And I was
политик политик например да меня А меня
specifically interested in the politician Trump and
политик конкретно Трамп заинтересовал и
accordingly I watched this story
соответственно я посмотрел этот сюжет
So wait How could he
Так подожди Как он мог тебя
interest you if you are not interested in politics I
заинтересовать если ты политикой не
can't understand Well, I
интересуешься не могу понять Ну я
still understand that there were, for example,
всё-таки понимаю что были например
elections in  America and Trump won Well,
выборы в Америке и победил Трамп Ну это
even a person far from politics knows That
даже человек далёкий от политики знаю То
is, I know that well there were
есть я я знаю что ну был где-то там за
elections somewhere overseas Well, Trump won No, well,
океаном выборы Ну победил трам Нет ну ну
look, I'm not interested in politics, but
смотри вот я не интересуюсь политикой но
for example, I know that
я например знаю что всё-таки
Zelensky is the president of Ukraine and
президент Украины Зеленский а всё
I don't know the rest, for example, who's in the
остальное я например не знаю кто там в
Rada What Well, I know that there is a Rada in Ukraine
Раде Какие Ну я знаю что в Украине есть
but I don't know what parties are there
рада но я не знаю какие там есть партии
which are
какие
super super yes Well, of course you don't know
там супер супер да Ну конечно не знаешь
yes Question Well, why exactly Yes, well,
да Вопрос Ну почему именно Да ну вот
there is some Trump there he was elected He was
есть там какой-то Трамп он избирали его
elected even earlier And the point is
Его ж ещё раньше было избирали А смысл
Why are you
те Почему ты
l well, how how how to say Here Imagine
л ну как как как сказать Вот Представь
you ask why you listen to this
теб спросить вот почему ты слушаешь эту
music or Why did you read this book
музыку или Почему ты прочитал эту книгу
very simply yes why did I read this
очень просто да почему я прочитал эту
book Yes, I'll explain because I wanted to
книгу Да объясню потому что я хотел
get such and such information on
получить такую такую информацию на
such and such a topic No, well, that is, you You
такую-то какую-то тему Нет ну то есть ты
look That is, you do something so that
Ты смотри То есть ты что-то делаешь
you have something specifically That is, to
чтобы у тебя конкретно что-то было Вот
get some benefit or
именно какую-то пользу получить или
something that is, that is,
чтото вот а то есть ты для наслаждения
you watched about Trump for Well, not for
ты о трампе смотрел для Ну не для
enjoyment, the most most most interest
наслаждения интерес самый самый самый
simple interest I became interested in the
простой интерес мне стало интересно
question yes Question can you name me five
вопрос да Вопрос можешь мне назвать пять
questions that have become interesting to you about
вопросов которые тебе стали интересны по
your domestic policy of Russia over the
твоей внутренней политике России за
past
последний
year m five
год м пять
questions that have become interesting to you in your
вопросов что тебе стало во твоей
domestic policy of Russia over the
внутренней политике России интересно за
past year Well the dollar exchange rate for example So
последний год Ну курс доллара например
what next could there be another
дальше что может быть ещё
mortgage
ипотека
perhaps
возможно
Although again
Хотя опять
rather the dollar exchange rate and actually that's
же скорее курс доллара и собственно на
all That is to say you seriously could not
всё То есть ты на полном серьёзе не смог
name five topics that have
назвать пять тем которые за последний
interested you over the past year have become
год тебя заинтересовали стали тебе
interesting to you in your policy where you
интересными в твоей политике где ты
live look again I'm telling you
живёшь смотри ещё раз я тебе говорю
initially my position is this truth -
изначально моя позиция такая правда -
this is what can be checked here is everything that
это то что можно проверить вот всё что
here I'll open a hypothetical YouTube Well let's
вот я открою условный YouTube Да ну
take YouTube because I
возьмём там YouTube потому что я оттуда
get information from there I'll look at
информацию получаю я буду посмотреть
some bloggers they will say one thing I'll
одних блогеров они будут говорить одно Я
look at other bloggers and they will
посмотрю вторых блогеров и они будут
say something else right now there I
говорить другое вот сейчас там я вот
see you Well how Well it's obvious you are
вижу ты Ну как Ну видно про украинский
set up about the Ukrainian I don't know who this blogger is
настроен я не знаю кто это блогер бло
really Yes unexpectedly unexpectedly Well
действительно Да неожиданно неожиданно
you will naturally
Да вот ты естественно
say your approach and naturally you
скажешь свой подход и естественно у тебя
will have some facts figures open
будут какие-то факты цифры открыть
another one there And by the way I can also
другого там А кстати ещё ещё могу
say I came across some I think
сказать попадалась мне какая-то по-моему
her name is Panchenko here I remembered  I
Панченко её зовут вот я я вспомнил
came across one like that too, I think it was Panchin, I
попадалась такая тоже по-моему панчин я
could be
могу
wrong. She is Well, or similar bloggers will
ошибаться она Ну или подобные блогеры
say something else. Now look, look at
скажут другое Вот теперь смотри смотри
what
какой
moment, on the one hand, there will be one piece of
момент с одной стороны будет одна
information, on the other hand, there will be a
информация другая с другой стороны будет
different view and completely different
Другой взгляд и совершенно другая
information. Now tell me what it will give me, what
информация теперь скажи вот что мне даст
I know, the
что я знаю лава
government's lava, and Misha, what it will
правительства а Мишу вот что это мне
give me, super, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, that
даст супер стоп стоп стоп стоп стоп
means,
значит
uh, specifically real information,
ээ конкретно реальная информация тебе
it won't give you anything. Yes, and some
это ничего не даст Да вот а какие-то
bloggers from Ukraine, Spain, Russia, no,
блогеры из Украины Испании России не нет
look, I came here to talk to an
смотри я пришёл сюда чтобы пообщаться с
ordinary person, so
обычным человеком то что я натыкаюсь вот
I come across a Ukrainian blogger. I just don't. Well, I see
на украинского блогера Мне просто не Ну
you're looking, no. You're looking on
я смотрю ты смотришь нет Ты смотришь в
YouTube. Some kind of [ __ ],
юбе Да какого-то там шмар ещё там
someone else, yeah, like, well, I don't watch. He may be in
кого-то да типа ну я я не смотрю он у
my recommendations.
меня в рекомендации
Yes, IK is a story, but it's not my
у можеть Да ИК это сюжет но это не моя
environment. So look again. I just,
сре так смотри ещё раз я просто вот
when I live in Ukraine, I can name a bunch of
когда я живу в Украине Да я могу кучу
options that interest me in
вариантов назвать что меня интересует во
domestic politics. Yes, you're a person
внутренней политике Да ты человек
who lives in Russia, but you couldn't
который живёт в России да не смог
name it, you could only name the dollar exchange rate
назвать то смог назвать только курс
and the
доллара и
mortgage. You couldn't name the questions
ипотека ты не смог назвать п вопросов
that interest you.  in the inner Poli
которые тебя как во внутренней Поли
for a year yes that is you are a person
на протяжении года да то есть ты человек
who is generally removed from all
который вообще отстранён от всех
news and politics Absolutely Yes I
новостей и политики Абсолютно Да я это
admit it but for some reason you yes you watch
признаю но почему-то ты да ты смотришь
some political issues in
каких-то политические там вопросы в
another country you are interested in Trump you are
другой стране тебя интересует Трамп тебя
interested in what is going on with the
интересует что там с
TCC look with the TCC I am interested in
тцк смотри с тцк Мне интересно
how how what is really happening with
как как что действительно происходит у
ordinary people here are the most
обычных вот самых
I am talking to you Yes you are interested in what is
смот я говор тебя Да тебя интересует что
happening with the Ukrainians what is happening with the
происходит у украинцев что происходит у
Americans Yes why are you not interested in
американцев Да почему тебя не интересует
what is happening with
что происходит у
you here you did not think look you did not think
тебя вот ты не думал смотри ты Не думал
here is a very simple thing look I am
вот очень простая такая вещь смотри мне
interested in you as an ordinary Russian did
интересно у тебя как простого россиянина
you think how much money a day Russia
ты думал сколько денег в день Россия
spends on the war in Ukraine and how much for
тратит на войну в Украине и сколько за
this money it was possible to build and
эти деньги можно было всего построить и
buy in Russia in your city
купить в России в твоём городе
I and failure This thought that is of
у меня и провала Эта мысль то есть
course it is understandable this whole war is for
конечно понятное дело вся эта война она
something Well it is paid for with something And what
за чтото Ну она чем-то опла А какие
amounts what is the order of the amounts I did not
суммы какие это порядок сумм не
try to google ask bloggers
попробовал погуглить у блогеров спросить
some Well they will be different here
каких-то Ну они же будут разные вот я
even now I can just climb there
даже сейчас могу залезть просто там
right here in front of you I climbed yes Well look
прямо вот при тебе залез да Ну смотри
very Look for example there is
очень Посмотреть например есть
official data How much  for
официальные данные Сколько стоит
example, about an armored personnel carrier, how much a rocket costs
например о БТР та сколько ракета стоит
Yes, and look at how much they spend per month, the
Да и посмотреть сколько их в месяц
minimum estimate Yes, and
примерно уходит минимальная оценка Да и
then look at And how much does it cost to
потом посмотреть А сколько стоит
build, for example,
построить например
apartments for people How much does it cost to
квартиры для людей Сколько стоит школу
build a school and calculate what could be
построить и посчитать что можно было
done in Tambov for this money,
сделать в Тамбове за эти деньги вот
can you name five problems of
можешь мне назвать пять проблем
Tambov? Well, of course, roads,
Тамбова Ну конечно дороги
housing, what, housing and communal services Well, most likely this Well,
жильё что ну ЖКХ Ну скорее всего это Ну
this may be related to
это может быть связано с
roads, jobs, naturally
дорогами рабочие места естественно
How many have I already named p
Сколько уже я назвал п
enough, what else do we have, well, medicine,
доста что у нас ещё ну медицина
naturally, since school, as if it were
естественно так как школа
possible, school Well, this This is a
яко возможно школа Ну это Это
standard set, you are not interested
стандартный набор вот тебя не интересует
How to make it so that you become Better,
Как сделать так чтобы у вас стали Лучше
at least a little, roads, at least a
хоть чуть-чуть дороги хоть лучше
little,
чуть-чуть
better, I am also not interested How can we
меди меня также не интересует Как там
stop the war there,
наме остановить войну
e Because I have no way to
е Потому что у меня нет возможности на
influence it somehow, that is, Imagine, are
это как-то влиять то есть Представь вот
you interested in life on Mars or in
интересует ли тебя жизнь на Марсе или
bringing out some kind of bacteria there or there To
вывести какую-то бактерию там или там
create some kind of virus or, on the contrary, an
Создать какой-то там вирус или наоборот
antibiotic That's why you are not
антибиотик Вот почему тебя это не
interested in this because you do not have the
интересует потому что у тебя нет
opportunity to do this Why am I
возможности это делать почему меня
interested in life on Mars I was thinking about
интересует жизнь на Марса Я размышлял об
this And why are you not interested, for
этом А почему тебя не интересует
example, there is life on Uranus, life is great Well,
например там жизнь на уране жизнь на ура
Uranus  Uranus on Uranus Yes, I'm interested I
Ну уране Уран на уране Да интересует Я
even look I myself at school Olympiads in
даже смотри я сам в школе олимпиады по
physics and then I went to all sorts of I
физики да потом ходил всякие я
calculate The thing is that
высчитывать Там дело в том что
life in such a form as ours is impossible
невозможна жизнь в такой форме как у нас
because of the very strong due to the large
потому что очень сильная из-за большой
mass of the planet strong force of
массовой планеты сильная сила земного
gravity Yes, just like on Jupiter, a
притяжения Да так как и на Юпитере
person Just
то человека Просто
flatten I'm interested in
расплющить я интересуюсь
not Hang out I'm not interested in this Yes, I'm
не Зависай меня это интересует не Да
interested in this but I can't understand
меня это интересует но я не могу понять
why you who are not interested in anything
почему тебя которые не интересует ничего
In general, yes, in my country,
Вообще да в своей стране
yes I'm interested in those things that, so
да Меня интересуют те вещи которые так
to speak, I may just be
скажем мне может быть за ними просто
interested in watching them And why are you interested in watching
интересно понаблюдать А почему тебе
Trump and not
интересно понаблюдать за трампом а не
interested in watching Look, this is on the
интересно понаблюдать за Смотри это на
level I'm also
уровне Я же
after Putin Most likely I somewhere
теже за Путиным Скорее всего я где-то
something and maybe I saw here here I'm
что-то и может быть и видел тут тут
just not going to lie there somewhere
просто я не буду там врать где-то Может
Maybe something I don't get into I don't get into I'm not
быть что-то я не вникаю не вникаю не
interested exactly so deeply so that
интересуюсь именно так глубоко чтобы
okay, what did you watch about
хорошо ладно что что ты смотрел про
Trump, something interested you about
трампа что-то тебя интересовало про
Trump Well  Last Let's say
трампа Ну Последний Так скажем какой-то
they had some
у них там был в Белом
meeting with President Zelensky in the White House and
доме встреча с президентом Зеленским и
some scandal happened so so super
произошёл какой-то скандал так так супер
That is, look, you were interested in the
То есть смотри тебе тебе интересна была
meeting between Trump and Zelensky yes yes Super
встреча трампа и Зеленского да да Супер
And can you say remember with whom
А можешь сказать вспомнить с кем
Putin met, for example, during the
встречался Путин например на протяжении
year, at least with
года хоть хоть с
someone
кем-то
now I probably won't
сейчас наверное я не будет на этот
answer this question here's the question look, you were
вопрос ответить вот вопрос смотри тебе
n't interested at all in who the president of your
вообще не интересовало президент твоей
country was meeting with there with the Taliban with
страны с кем встречается там с талибам с
Myanmar and so on Next Yes And for some reason I was
мьянмой и так Дальше Да А почему-то
interested because the
заинтересовала потому что встречается
president of some country Ukraine and
президент какой-то страны Украины и
Russia, which is America, is meeting look if
России который Америки смотри если бы
I saw something like a fly out somewhere in the news Well,
мне где-то в новостях что-то
not in the recommendations that there
типа выле Ну не в рекомендациях что там
was some kind of conditional scandal in the Kremlin
в кремле был какой-то условный скандал
How did you even know that Zelensky
Откуда ты вообще узнал что Зеленский
met with Trump somewhere in the White House
где-то с трампом встречался в Белом доме
Well, in the recommendations it was in the
Ну в рекомендациях это было же
recommendations so and in the recommendation And on
рекомендациях так а в рекомендация А у
which channel and which blogger did you
какого канала у какого блогера ты это
watch this Not an ordinary YouTube recommendations
смотрел Не обычный YouTube рекомендации
they go accordingly that is my
они идут соответственно то есть моя
topic the topic of my interests I already
тематика тематика моих интересов Я уже
said it's music Well, keep in mind on
сказал это музыка Да ну Имей в виду на
which channel  you saw this
каком канале ты это увидел эту
recommendation from some blogger or
рекомендацию у какого-то блогера или там
in the news Maxim Katz I'm telling you but
в новостях Максим Кац же говорю а вот
Maxim Katz and you watched Maxim
Максим Кац и ты посмотрел таки Максима
Katz Maxim Katz I watched
Кац Максим Кац Я посмотрел
accordingly he released several
соответственно там он выпустил несколько
videos one of them I watched Yeah about
роликов один из них я посмотрел Угу про
Trump And why are you
именно трампа А почему ты вот именно
watching all sorts of recommendations And you
смотри тебе всякие рекомендации Да и ты
clicked on Maxim Katz
кликнул типа именно на Максима каца
Trump Why are you triggered You don't really know who
Трамп Почему тебе триг Ты не знаешь кто
Trump is what they do
такой Трамп толком что они занимается
No I look I know who Trump is he is the
Нет я смотри я знаю кто такой Трамп это
president of the United States of America know
президент Соединённых Штатов Америки зна
Yes you know Well there is a president Well
Да вот ты знаешь Ну есть президент
that's a strange question Well how how to
Ну это странный вопрос Ну как как
say Here you are interested in something You to
сказать Вот тебя что-то заинтересовал Ты
why that is what triggered you
к почему вот что что тебя триггернуло
there was a naked girl in the picture or
там голая девчонка была на картинке или
what
что с
with the consequences I can even
го с последствиями я даже могу сейчас в
open the story now Well come on let's sort you out three
истории открыть А ну давай что тебя три
Now
разберём Сейчас
a second well yes Trump and Zelensky
секунду ну да вот Трамп и Зеленский
had a fight what will happen next 4 days ago
поругались что будет дальше 4 дня назад
Yes And what is it about Regina Well scold you no I'm
Да А что тебя это Регину Ну поругать не
not lying I'm lying I'm lying I'm lying Trump's boorish conversation
не вру вру вру вру вру хамский разговор
and  Zelensky What happened in the
трампа и Зеленского Что произошло в
White House that's what Well I just don't
Белом доме вот та что Ну я просто не
understand how this can interest a
понимаю как это может заинтересовать
person who is not interested in
человека который не интересуется
politics Yes, it's very simple, most likely
политикой Да очень просто скорее всего
some videos Maybe there is
какие-то ролики Может быть там и про
something about our politics somewhere I may have
нашу политику где-то я что-то может быть
watched something but I don't take it into
и смотрел но я не не беру это во
account I don't even take it into account Well, or
внимание Я не беру даже во внимание Ну
rather, let's say I don't take it On Vera, even
вернее так скажем я не беру На Веру даже
this video There is Maxim
вот этот ролик Там Максима
Katsi That is, if I, like, I don't remember now,
каци То есть если мне вот я я сейчас не
saw this video about tsk I'm not saying
видел этот ролик про тцк Я же не говорю
that you have tsk operating there in Ukraine I
что у вас там в Украине орудуют тцк Я
even tsk again look And what does tsk mean
даже тцк ещё раз смотри А что означает
in general And I'm telling you about this I do
тцк вообще А я тебе про это говорю я
n't even know how to decipher it we don't
даже не знаю как это расшифровать у нас
have anyone Well, look, in Ukraine I do
нету никого Ну смотри у нас в Украине Я
n't know I saw some look Russian
не знаю я видел какие-то смотри русские
bloggers write we don't have anything like that at all
блогеры пишут у нас нету вообще такого к
Look, look, you're telling me right now
Вот вот смотри вот ты мне сейчас как раз
That's how I check information I
говоришь Вот как я проверяю информацию
saw the Central Committee project I'm going to the beginning everything, yes,
вот увидел проект ЦК я иду в чале всё да
look we don't know we don't  we know i
смотри мы не знаем мы не знаем я
explain i as a common man i speak i
объясняю я как простой человек я говорю
for the first time i heard only from russian
я впервые я только от российских
bloggers that we have some kind of
блогеров слышал что у нас есть какие-то
tsk what is tsk here now look
тцк что такое тцк вот вот теперь смотри
here i looked i talked to
вот я посмотрел я Пообщался с
several people they really
несколькими людьми они действительно
said no tsk z all yes we have
сказали нет никаких тцк з всё да у нас
more than that yes for some reason russian
больше того да почему-то российские
bloggers there all these people in the chat letke
блогеры там вот эти все люди в чату
say that our president is
летке говорят что у нас президент
Zelensky we have Zelensky not the president
Зеленский у нас Зеленский не президент
this is on youtube who shows you like that And who is
это вам в юбе кто так показывает А кто у
your president then Tymoshenko is
вас президент тогда Тимошенко
not Tymoshenko is the president Well you Look you
нет Тимошенко президент Ну тыж Смотри ты
asked me a real Ukrainian
ж спросил у меня у реального украинца
who is our Tymoshenko is the president now Well then
кто нас Тимошенко сейчас президент Ну
this does not correspond to
значит это не соответствует
reality Because if i go for
действительности Потому что если я иду
example to the same Wikipedia there will be a
например в ту же Википедию там будет
president Wikipedia What Wikipedia who
президент Википедия Что Википедия кто
wants to rule there wait a hundred And what were
хочет там и правит подожди сто А ты что
you looking for in Wikipedia Who is the president of
ты искал в Википедии Кто президент
Ukraine no Look Well wait stop I
Украины нет Смотри Ну подожди стоп Я
suppose because Where are you from look you
предполагаю потому Откуда ты смотри ты
saw some video that the president of Ukraine I
увидел какой-то ролик что президент укра
will show that the president of Ukraine Yanukovych will you
покажу что президент Украины Янукович ты
believe that the thing is that i don't believe i
поверишь в том дело что я не верю я
left Yes  look you came out to
те вышел Да смотри ты вышел что чтоб
ask real Ukrainians if there is such a thing
спросить у реальных украинцев есть такое
or not Ask me who is the president of Ukraine the
или нет Спроси у меня кто президент
president of Ukraine Tymoshenko I
украи президента Украины Тимошенко я
understood No How not Well no no the president of
понял Не Как нет Ну вот нет нет
Ukraine is not Tymoshenko no then the
президент Украины не Тимошенко нет то
president Ruslan Koshulynsky all the
президент Руслан кошулинский вот тем
more so look here I am with this information
более вот смотри вот я с этой информацие
accordingly here is the next one I Well when
соответственно вот следующий я Ну когда
I go to
я пойду
turn the page Ruslan there is some kind of this I have
перелистнуть Руслан там какой-то это я
already even forgotten about him here is Oleg GBO what kind of Ruslan is
уже даже забыл про него вот Олег ГБО
now Oleg GBO president
какой Руслан сейчас Олег ГБО президент
GBO how would I like
ГБО как мне
this 5 minutes ago president And
этон бы 5 минут назад президентом А
now Oleg GBO Now Oleg Tyagnibok
теперь Олег ГБО Вот теперь Олег Тягнибок
how can I check this information
как мне эту информацию
Ask a Ukrainian Ask
проверить Спроси у украинца Спроси у
me here I asked an ordinary Ukrainian
меня вот я спросил у обычного украинца
he answered me this Well accordingly
он мне вот это ответил Ну соответственно
I see that really Listen just for the sake of
я вижу что действительно Слушай вот ради
interest here is a very good Let's
интереса вот очень хороший Давай
try such a game ask Go to chat
попробуем такую игру спроси Заходи в чат
roulette and ask each Ukrainian Is it
рулетка и у каждого украинца спроси
true that Russians Here ask me
Правда ли что русские Вот спроси у меня
how you Ukrainians Well this is a
как вы украинцев Ну это это
provocative question ssi with
провокационный вопрос сси с
came out I ask you this is the same question
вышел Я тебя спрашиваю это вопрос тойже
and your mother knows what you see  burnt
а твоя мама знает что ты видишь подгорел
podgos ssi me or do we consider Russians
подго сси меня или считаем мы русских
ask Well why do I need a wire
спроси Ну зачем мне прово
but by the way by the way Ask yes ask
а вот кстати вот кстати Спроси да спроси
how do we treat ru how how you well
как мы относимся к ру как как вот ты ну
not you Because you are here Yes I have un to
не вы Потому что ты здесь Да у меня ун к
ordinary Russian people Yes it means I
обычным русским вот людям Да значит я
think that
считаю что
you like you yes you sit pretending to be a
Вы как ты да ты сидишь притворяешься
person who is not interested in
человеком который не это не интересуется
politics You are interested in everything You
политикой Всё ты интересуешься Всё ты
understand everything you justify murder
разбираешься ты оправдываешь убийство
genus I told you justify
род я тебе рассказал оправдываешь
[laughter]
[смех]
divine roast like squeak comment
божественна прожарка лайк писка комент
subscribe to my Telegram right now
подпишись на мий Telegram прямо зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg Orcs in your ban and very
нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и дуже
many videos are not shown to
багато видео не показують
people sometimes do not show information about
людям вчасно не показуе информация про
ST so that we Mali operational
СТ тому для того щоб ми Мали оперативный
links are written right now and while there are in
звязок пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в
Telegram OKM videos there are also interesting and
телегра окм видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we are sorry  you
корисна информация и ми повинни з вами
trimati permanent operational connection
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that chi will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава Украине пись